SOME OF THESE EVENTS DID HAPPEN…
In 1986, Mexico was facing a crisis.
Unemployment, political dissatisfaction
and other issues plagued the nation.
But for a month that year,
my country was the center of the universe.
…the best play of the World Cup.
Goal!
Because that was where the greatest
World Cup of all time took place.
Mexico '86 was a cultural phenomenon,
an unparalleled celebration.
From then on, soccer changed worldwide.
The fan base exploded,
the spectacle grew,
and the business became stronger.
And do you know
who made the Cup what it has become?
Yeah, I did.
But you don't know me.
You were told the wrong story.
-…from the referee?
-Don't insult me.
You and I can exchange information. Fine.
But if dirty tactics come into play,
everything change s. Come on.
This is sacred to me, dude.
The field is sacred.
11 versus 11, that's all.
Start recording.
Let's see, the use of manuals.
That's where the…
We'll pick this up in a second.
Sir, how are you doing?
Hey, José Ramón. Nice gossip circle, huh?
Anything juicy?
No, we're doing an interview
about the manuals we're introducing.
Listen, whatever intel he's giving you,
don't pay him too much.
Your show
has a tight budget anyway, right?
You want me to work extra?
What did we agree on?
Mr. Gustavo, I knew it.
The charts, right? Yeah.
I told you. If you include charts,
people won't read 'em.
That's the point, sir.
If they don't read the article,
where do they find the details?
In the charts.
Who do you think reads this crap?
De la Torre? As if!
It's just a formality.
Rewrite it. And quit arguing.
Hello. Good afternoon.
Hello, ma'am.
Is your husband home?
No.
But tell me… who are you?
I'm Hugo Sánchez.
Sorry. I didn't recognize you.
Have you put on weight?
It's just that…
Madrid food doesn't agree with me.
So…
what brings you here?
I'm here to
score a little goal.
Come in. You're running late.
-Don't you have a match?
-Yeah, let's warm up first.
Honey, are you really going
to shut me out? Huh?
Oh no!
I'll knock this shit down.
-That lamp belonged to my grandma.
-Really?
Let's see.
-Listen…
-What?
Would you go to Club Med?
Damn, did they cancel on you again?
As you can see, some people
don't give a damn about losing money.
Which one is it?
The one in Playa Blanca?
Yeah.
Sounds good, huh?
When is it?
In two weeks.
No way, Susana.
Weren't you going to fix the leak?
Yeah. Exactly. I handled it.
A bucket, seriously?
You didn't see that coming.
So, what do you say?
Should I confirm or not?
I do like the idea, you know?
The beach.
-The sunshine.
-Oh, with you.
Open bar.
-My conga beats.
-Yuck, your congas.
My coconut oil,
which you love to rub on me.
Coconut oil.
-You know what?
-What?
I'm staying a bit longer.
What are you doing?
-Hugo.
-What?
-Get out.
-Come on.
-The match is over, Hugo.
-What about penalties?
You never win on penalties. Move.
-What a bitch.
-Just go.
No one said that, Mom.
Actually, if you want,
Paulina and I
could live here, in this house.
You know? Freaking Álvarez
asked me to redo the quarterly reports.
Three weeks collecting data,
and the jerk asks me to remove the charts.
If it were up to him,
we'd still be in 1970.
-Jeez. You're still hung up on the charts?
-What?
It's a matter of life or death, right?
It's simple. Your boss
doesn't like charts, don't do them.
If you don't like how they treat you,
just quit freaking FEMEXFUT.
-I'm just telling you about it.
-So stop telling me about it.
I don't want to hear about it.
I'm too tired.
I had a shitty day too,
and I'm not dumping it on you.
Oh, poor thing.
Your day must have been so hard.
How many damn years
have I put up with all your complaints?
Smiling and all.
-"My job. It's too much, I can't do it."
-Wait.
They fired the whole accounting team,
and we got all their work.
I know, Beatriz, I know. Like 13,540 times
I've had to listen to your damn whining.
And I'm still here, not making a fuss.
You make a fuss
just by walking through that door.
Oh, I'm going to bed.
I have an early meeting tomorrow.
Mediocre at home, mediocre at work.
But something
was about to happen in Colombia
that would change my life forever.
Violence continues to surge in Bogotá.
Two attacks were reported today,
carried out by criminal groups,
paralyzing the country.
In response,
President Belisario Betancur announced…
The 1986 World Cup
will not be held in Colombia.
Colombia has just announced
that they will not host the World Cup.
Of course, just as I told you.
Yes, I know we had
all the paperwork ready to send to Bogotá,
but that's life.
-Oh, well.
-Fuck.
So where will it be?
It has to be
on this side of the ocean, right?
What? The Americans?
They've thrown their hat in,
but who else wants in?
Who, sir?
Us, the Mexicans.
Cañedo called me,
and they just made it official.
We are going to Switzerland
to bring home the '86 World Cup.
That's good news, isn't it?
Do you know how many countries
have hosted the World Cup
twice?
-None.
-Exactly! None.
How ridiculous is it to go to FIFA
to fight for a World Cup
that's not meant for us?
That's just Cañedo and Azcárraga
thinking that dropping money on FIFA
will get us the World Cup.
What a stupid waste of time.
All right, then… I'm going to Switzerland,
but on vacation.
Let me know who wants some chocolates.
The match…
Hey, switch it to the soap opera.
Chava. Chava? Cha…
Look, it's about to start.
-Buddy…
-What is it?
What's with this lady?
She just asked Chava
to put on the soap opera. No way.
Put the game on.
The second half is starting.
It's soap opera time.
What is this, buddy?
What is this? A soccer bar.
Yes, it is, but…
But what?
I'll tell her. Should I tell her?
-I'll tell her myself.
-No. Martín.
We'll switch it now. Wait. Relax.
"Relax." No way. "Relax."
The national team is playing.
The national team.
This is a soccer bar.
Then go watch it at home.
This is home for me, ma'am.
Here. I went to high school here.
I've been coming here for 20 years.
Sorry, sir.
We don't have to watch whatever you want.
Nobody watches the game here.
-Want to watch it? Turn on the soap opera.
-They're losing.
Apparently, this is a soap opera bar now.
Damn it, José Ramón,
how much information have I leaked to you?
-You owe me.
-Leaking isn't selling.
And I already know
that Mexico is going after the World Cup.
No, this is a scoop, man, a bombshell.
Or I wouldn't be calling you.
I'm doing it
because of our damn friendship.
Out of mutual respect, dude,
I'm giving it to you. This is pure gold.
You know what? Forget it, dude.
I'm going with Juan Dosal.
He offered me a slot on Sunday.
You're going to the competition, asshole?
You're giving me no choice, man.
I don't want to.
But look how you're treating me.
Listen, will you?
How long have we known each other?
How many years, damn it?
Fine. I can have you on for five minutes.
-Come over right now.
-Oh, perfect.
Perfect, dude.
Where are you going?
José Ramón Fernández is interviewing me.
Yeah, right.
Are you… Are you taking the car?
I have aerobics.
-Hi.
-You? Now?
-It's not Thursday.
-No.
-Are you going out?
-Yes.
I wanted to invite…
-That skirt is so pretty.
-Thank you.
You never wear red lipstick.
It looks good.
I want to invite you…
I'm being interviewed on TV now.
I mean, in two hours.
-No wonder you're dressed up.
-Ever been to a TV set? Where you off to?
Out to dinner.
Not for work, clearly.
Is it with your friends or…
Are you going dancing after, or what?
Look, Martín. Are you throwing a tantrum?
-Not at all.
-And it's your day with your wife, right?
Hey. Hi.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
You look gorgeous.
Are you going to dinner with this kid?
Yeah. His name is Óscar.
We're going to Quetzal.
I'm going to an interview.
As I said, with José Ramón Fernández.
-That's great, neighbor.
-José Ramón is a journalist.
You took my leg warmers out of the car?
-I did.
-I asked you not to, Martín.
-Hey. Good evening.
-Hi. Is that your wife?
I'm Susana from apartment six.
Your husband…
Martín, right? He was just giving me
his plumber's number,
to deal with the leaks.
-So you're the neighbor with the leaks.
-Yeah.
That plumber is a crook.
Right?
Yes. He is.
-All right… Should we go?
-Let's go.
Thank you, neighbor.
Nice to meet you, ma'am.
Miguel, good luck with that interview.
-Where did you put them?
-Huh?
-My leg warmers. Where did you put them?
-In the dresser.
I asked you not to touch my stuff.
I'm running super late.
Good evening.
Welcome to the wide world of sports.
Today we have an exclusive for you.
Martín de la Torre is here with us
in the studio.
He's one of the key men at FEMEXFUT.
Martín, we know
Mexico has stated its intention
to host the '86 World Cup,
and its toughest competitor is the US.
What will the Federation's strategy
with FIFA be?
That's the problem.
We don't have a strategy.
It's important
that your audience knows the truth,
that FEMEXFUT is showing no interest
in bringing the World Cup to Mexico,
which is by no means easy.
What do you mean?
The lack of interest.
The lack of commitment.
There is no faith in the abilities
of a man like Emilio Azcárraga.
It needs to be said.
But what's even worse is the lack of trust
in this country's capabilities.
Beyond your personal feelings,
the federation
has neglected Mexican soccer for years.
Well said.
And it all comes from the top,
from the leadership.
Are you referring to
FEMEXFUT's president, Gustavo Álvarez?
Look, this is a historic moment, okay?
FIFA has its eye on Mexico.
But first, we have to get rid
of people like Mr. Álvarez
and his entourage of mediocre officials
who've dragged soccer this low.
Are you campaigning?
That's a great question.
No, not at all. Who am I to do that?
No, I'm an official, an official
willing to devote his life to soccer.
I want to work for this nation,
wherever this nation needs me.
You heard him.
Martín de la Torre has formally denounced
his boss at FEMEXFUT.
That's a bold claim, Martín.
We'll be back after the break.
I told you to quit,
not to sacrifice yourself
on national TV, Martín.
I'm taking control of my career.
What career, Martín?
Who's going to match your pay?
You're a clerk.
I'm a certified accountant, okay?
I have a career.
Collecting jobs you hate is not a career.
You have a problem, Susana. A big one.
-Susana?
-You don't believe in me.
I think you think I'm stupid.
'Cause you keep pulling stupid stunts.
Hello.
Yes, he lives here.
I'm calling on behalf of Mr. Azcárraga.
I'm sorry, who?
-Azcárraga's secretary.
-Yes. One second.
It's Emilio Azcárraga's secretary.
-Really?
-I knew it. You screwed up.
Hello.
Mr. De la Torre?
Mr. Emilio. Thank you for seeing me.
It's clear that you want
to sabotage your boss's job.
But please, explain to me
why I should give you the position.
Speak up, you bastard. Come on.
It's no secret that FEMEXFUT
is in full decline, Mr. Emilio.
Just look at the data.
We didn't qualify for the '74 World Cup.
In '78, we were in last place.
'82, we failed to qualify again.
Did I ask you for a report
on our team's shitty situation?
No, of course not.
Look, I like people who are ballsy.
You've proved it by going on that dwarf's
show to call out your boss.
But I also like people who are creative,
so I'll ask you plainly.
What's your plan?
Imagine Mexican soccer were yours.
Imagine? It is mine, bastard.
Loyalty.
That's what I'm offering.
I've heard you say
that you're a PRI soldier.
Well, I'm here
to offer myself up as your soldier.
I'm going to bust my ass
to bring the World Cup to Mexico.
Loyalty. Okay. That's your plan?
Holy shit.
Loyalty is the bare minimum.
Ask those who aren't loyal to me
how they're doing.
If loyalty is all you have to offer,
you're not the right person.
Get out, please.
Get out, you bastard.
Do you know how many Latin Americans
have been FIFA presidents, Mr. Emilio?
One. Havelange.
Exactly.
How did he get there?
Are you testing me, you bastard?
Havelange got to FIFA
by being a piece of shit.
Not only that.
Do you know what put him on the map?
Mexico '70. Winning the Cup with Brazil.
That put him on the map
and got him that seat.
That's what I want, Mr. Emilio.
I want to be FIFA president.
Put me in charge of FEMEXFUT,
and I'll bring the World Cup to Mexico.
And maybe the boys
might be inspired by playing at home
and win the Cup for us.
No way.
Mexico wouldn't win a Cup,
not even playing 11 versus three.
Yeah, maybe I got carried away.
But what has never happened
is one country hosting
the World Cup twice.
That will put us on the map.
The best broadcast, via your satellite.
The first World Cup
run by private enterprise.
We'll make history, Mr. Emilio.
And I want to be by your side.
Good thing dreaming is free, right?
You want Havelange's job
for the glory, huh?
For the money.
So people stop you
on the street for a picture.
I'm surrounded by people like you.
People who need to be loved.
-To be told they matter.
-Yeah.
Very profitable people, right?
I mean, because
everything you have,
you owe it to them, right?
With all due respect.
I'm telling you, you are ballsy.
Look,
if I put you in charge of FEMEXFUT,
you go to FIFA
and fail to bring me the World Cup,
I will personally make sure
that every door closes on you.
Basically, your life
will become a nightmare. Is that clear?
-Damn, crystal clear, Mr. Emilio.
-Good. Let's get to work.
I won't let you down, Mr. Emilio. Okay?
You got Azcárraga to fire me,
didn't you, asshole?
Congratulations.
Every rise has its fall.
No. Me, I'm going to work, asshole.
The badge.
You'll see what's coming to you, prick.
Good afternoon.
Let's bring some dignity
back to this federation.
Mayrita, good afternoon.
Listen up, gentlemen.
This. This is how
you wear the badge, okay?
Well done, Mayrita. Well done.
Hello, Martín.
Mr.… Mr. Guillermo Cañedo, damn it.
I'm sorry, Mr. Guillermo.
Pleasure. They offered you coffee, right?
Yes, thank you.
How embarrassing.
Gustavo didn't take the news very well.
I hope he didn't take
the paperclips, that jerk.
-Did you see your chair?
-Yes.
We didn't replace it.
-Please, sit down.
-Sure.
I don't know if you remember,
we met at the Christmas toast.
1979. I got to shake your hand.
Emilio wants me in Switzerland with you.
FIFA wants us
to go this week and make our case.
That's… quite an honor, right?
Traveling with you.
We'll have a blast in Switzerland.
I have a few ideas
for the presentation here.
-But we can review them later.
-Yeah.
I've been there, Martín.
I've gotten us a World Cup before.
Listen to me,
and the second one will be ours. Easy.
Anything you say.
I'll follow your lead, okay?
Good. Get ready.
Since this will be your debut
in front of FIFA, bring your wife, okay?
Let them see you're a respectable man.
See you soon.
Martín!
-What is it?
-Come to Switzerland.
-I'm on a call.
-I'll be quick.
I was just named president of FEMEXFUT.
They want me to go to Switzerland
to bring the World Cup home.
So you're coming with me.
-You're drunk.
-No.
-And I'm on a call.
-Wait.
I am a little drunk.
-I'm on a call. Can I have a minute?
-I'll be quick.
Opportunities like this
only come once in a lifetime.
We have to go for it.
This isn't
some stupid urologist convention.
We're going to FIFA.
To try and get the World Cup. No biggie.
The World Cup, no way!
-Mexico!
-Please excuse me.
I'll call you right back, okay?
They asked me to bring my wife.
-So take her.
-I can't.
Why not?
I just asked her for a divorce.
Oh, you are really hammered, man.
I just had one tiny drink.
One drink, that's all.
I've been waiting my whole life for this.
Don't let me down.
I need you there. By my side.
-Just you and I, all alone.
-Right.
You want me by your side
so I'm not with anyone else.
What?
You keyed Óscar's car.
-Óscar? Óscar who?
-Óscar from yesterday.
-No…
-The one I went out with, right?
-The one you…? Oh, the kid.
-Yeah, you keyed his car.
-No, I don't remember.
-Martín, come on.
I'm not like that, Susana.
You keyed his car.
Go out with whoever you want.
-What?
-I mean it.
-Really?
-I'm quite open-minded.
I'm modern.
You'd never done it doggy style.
I'm never telling you a secret again.
It's just… What?
Am I the love of your life now?
Just listen to yourself.
You're the love of my life, Susana.
You are the love of my life.
You are the love of…
You want me to shout it out?
You are the love of my life, Susana!
Today, the Mexican delegation
travels to FIFA's headquarters in Zurich.
They will face the US delegation,
led by Jackie Ross,
billionaire Steve Ross's daughter,
who has brought none other than Pelé
and the controversial Henry Kissinger.
The Americans are going all in,
and in three days we'll know
which country will host the '86 World Cup.
ZURICH, SWITZERLAND, 1983
João.
-Guillermo, back from retirement.
-Only for you.
I finally met João Havelange.
He owns the World Cup.
My pleasure.
And then, the king.
The truth is,
Pelé is shorter than he looks on TV.
His boss, the gringa,
started showing off right away.
I love Mexico.
I was there with my dad
for the 1970 World Cup
What a fine tournament.
Too bad you didn't qualify for that Cup.
I mean, you didn't qualify
for eight World Cups.
Well, yeah. Henry Kissinger.
The last World Cup we went to
was in 1950, in Brazil.
So ironic, right?
I mean, the only goal you scored
in a World Cup
was scored by a Haitian.
A one-nil win against England,
with a goal by Joe Gaetjens.
Joe Maca.
Gaetjens.
-No. Maca.
-Gaetjens in the 38th minute.
I need to check that.
Nice to meet you, Mr. De la Torre.
A pleasure.
"A pleasure." Arrogant bitch. A pleasure?
We weren't backing down.
We immediately started gathering votes.
Congrats, Rogelio.
-You've done a great job with CONCACAF.
-Indeed.
That's why your support matters,
so that Mexico can host.
Egypt has played
one game in the World Cup. One.
In Mexico, you can play whoever you want.
Doctor Pereira always said
the idea of Third World countries
was invented by the Americans.
That's why we've always been good friends.
You know I love Mexico.
You also know
that not only do I run CONCACAF,
I was just appointed CFO
for Latin America.
CFO, where?
*********.
I've been there for eight years.
You have to look
beyond football, gentlemen.
The Libyan armed forces in Sudan.
President Mubarak
wants to help finish them.
Did you know Dr. Pereira
went to jail for selling expired vaccines?
I have orders from Atlanta
to vote for the Americans.
Kissinger spoke directly
to my CEO. I'm sorry.
The United States can help.
What do you offer?
Is he in jail?
Good night.
We love Mexico, but now it's time
for someone else to host.
SWEDEN
How can you vote for the Americans?
Aren't you Soviets?
USSR
Don't translate for him!
For fuck's sake! Let's go.
USA 12 - MEX 0
Perfect, thank you very much.
Yes, I'll wait here.
He's calling me back in five minutes.
That's great.
What are you going to say?
Mr. Azcárraga… No.
Let's see…
Mr. Azcárraga, I need money…
-It's urgent.
-No.
"Mr. Azcárraga."
Don't talk to him like he's your notary.
Let's see. Pretend that…
Pretend I'm him.
-What?
-What do you want?
What do you want?
You're there a day, and you screw up?
-Don't mess with me, Susana.
-Who the hell is Susana?
Are you with a broad?
You bastard.
I sent you there so you could focus.
-I'm very sorry.
-"I'm sorry"?
"I'm very sorry"?
Damn it, De la Torre.
You're someone's boss now.
Don't talk to me like you're my assistant.
I need more money, Emilio.
More?
What…? Who do you think I am?
You think I'm your ex
and I'm supposed to pay your bills?
Don't mess with me, Susana.
-Beatriz paid one year's rent.
-I don't give a shit.
What do you want, De la Torre?
Listen, Mr. Emilio, I…
No, I'm sorry, Emilio.
-I need for you to maybe lend me…
-"To maybe…" Maybe.
You've got no balls, De la Torre.
I don't know
who's got me by the balls anymore,
Susana or Emilio.
I'm confused.
Now I want to fuck Emilio Azcárraga.
Yes.
It's a…
-Pick up.
-Coming.
Hello.
I was in a meeting. What do you want?
Emilio…
I'm sorry to bother you,
but we need money.
We need money to negotiate.
This isn't going to work.
Yeah? Should I give you
a back rub while I'm at it?
The Americans rolled out the big guns,
and we're competing with pocket change.
How did today go?
-Good. Pretty good.
-No.
It went badly,
or you wouldn't be calling me.
What was it?
Did you offer something you don't have?
No.
Emilio, I'm sorry to say this,
but the problem is Mr. Guillermo Cañedo.
He's going around collecting favors
straight out of World War II.
It's crazy. Kissinger noticed.
They're wiping the floor with us.
Mr. Emilio…
I'm thinking, man.
Do you have a pen?
-Yeah, I'm all ears.
-I'll give you my bank's address.
Wait. No, wait. Listen to me first.
From now on, play it like we're winning.
Every time.
Even if we're going down,
talk like we're winning.
-Spend like we're winning.
-He sounds like you.
And celebrate like we're winning.
Understand?
-Absolutely, Mr. Emilio.
-Now jot this down.
Don't lose heart.
Come on. Let's go turn this around.
Let's go.
Here's the pledge to vote for Mexico
that you sent us three weeks ago.
It's the token of appreciation
we sent your way last week.
You show this to *********
as proof you committed to voting early.
-Can you change the date on a fax?
-Come on, Rogelio.
How would we do that?
For your cause.
You will pay for my team's expenses, okay?
No. There's plenty in there already.
It's okay. I'll cover the costs.
We celebrate like we're winning,
right, Mr. Guillermo?
Let's get to work.
Let's go, brother.
Come on.
One more!
Mexico!
Enough. We have
to go vote tomorrow, you suckers.
USA 4 - MEX 8
"The organization of the Cup
is regarded
as a matter of national interest
and international responsibility."
-What happened?
-We're screwed.
-Why?
-We lost Mozambique, Egypt, and the USSR.
Come in. Don't be seen like this.
What? How could that happen?
Kissinger offered Egypt missiles,
tripled our donation to Mozambique,
and got Pelé
to have dinner with Vasily Kuznetsov.
-With who?
-Vasily Kuz…
Look, it doesn't matter. We're screwed.
-What happened?
-Nothing, babe.
Go back to sleep.
Just sleep. It's nothing, really.
Mr. Guillermo, come on.
We made it this far for a reason.
You and I are going to fix this.
Fix this? Here's what's going to happen.
You do your presentation, say your crap.
The Egypt delegate will call you a moron.
The delegate from the Soviet Union
is also gonna call you a moron.
Just like the one from Mozambique.
And so on.
Everyone will call you a moron
so they won't be the moron
who didn't call you a moron.
You know what?
Let's go to FIFA. You and me. Now.
Our ride is coming in 45 minutes.
We'll take a cab. Come on, please.
Get ready. See you downstairs in five.
Remember, they can't see you like this.
We're winning.
-Five minutes. Go.
-Five minutes.
You were in the back.
Oh. You're early. Guillermo.
See you in a minute.
Thank you, Mr. FIFA President,
Mr. João Havelange.
A brother, a friend.
I'd like to start by pointing out
that Mexico has hosted a World Cup,
and not just any World Cup.
The greatest World Cup in history.
Where was King Pelé crowned? Mexico '70.
Where did the "Match of the Century,"
as the press called it, take place?
In my country. In Mexico '70.
And what have we done
for the past 13 years?
Expanded our infrastructure,
stepped up our preparation.
In Mexico, we're ready.
We've proven we're capable,
and, more importantly, we're eager.
You should know that few things matter
to us as much as soccer.
So today, you get to choose
between money and heart.
You will decide
whether the Cup is hosted by a country
that invades what it can't buy,
or by one where soccer defines who we are
and lives in our hearts.
Thank you very much.
That was a good PRI-style speech, right?
While this man talks,
let me tell you why I asked Cañedo
to arrive at FIFA before anyone else.
To reclaim the votes
the Americans snatched from us,
I had an idea.
I seated together all the delegates
I knew would vote for us.
That is, the ones
who weren't going to call me a moron.
Mexico.
My vote goes to Mexico.
And so, when they started hearing
"Mexico," "Mexico," "Mexico,"
the others realized the United States
might not get the majority after all.
Mexico.
Who's a big enough moron
to vote against the country
that clearly seems to be winning?
Mexico.
We absolutely crushed them.
I mean, it was insane.
The best part was going back to Mexico.
Who?
Who screwed the Americans? Huh?
Who screwed the Americans?
From that moment on,
El Tigre took over the World Cup.
From satellite broadcasts
to which brand of beer would be sold,
he was in charge.
Who's ballsy, huh? Who's ballsy?
It was a huge deal.
He gave me a life-changing bonus.
And we finally
had money to upgrade FEMEXFUT.
Agus!
-You're the best, Martín.
-Thank you.
Thanks. Thank you.
Thank you.
Goddammit, Mr. De la Torre!
-Freaking Cardozo. See, I told you so.
-You're the best, sir.
Can you take this, please?
You know what?
This applause is for Mayrita too.
Go, Mayrita!
Thank you.
Mayrita moved us into this office.
Thank you, Mayrita.
Many of you already know,
but it's important to celebrate it.
As of today, it's official.
The 1986 World Cup will be held in Mexico!
Thanks to you. To you.
Thank you.
What a legend.
Let's prove
what we're capable of in this country.
It hasn't been easy.
It has come at great cost,
even personal cost.
That's what I expect from you.
Exactly that.
I don't want hardworking people.
I want soldiers. Like Agus!
-Soldiers!
-Yeah!
I want soldiers! I want soldiers, damn it!
I want you to be a soldier!
We are going
to put on the best World Cup in history!
The second Mexican World Cup
has propelled
the transformative power of our nation.
Telecommunications,
tourism, infrastructure.
Economic momentum is surging,
and Mexico's
international standing seems unstoppable.
Today, the country pulses
with hope, pride, and national unity.
The eyes of the world are on Mexico,
thanks to the magic of soccer.
We were on top.
Being Mexican was seen as really cool.
As president of FEMEXFUT,
I am honored to be at the helm
of this phenomenon known as Mexico '86.
If the 1970 World Cup was important,
the 1986 World Cup will be historic.
At its peak, I was the man of the hour.
Everyone wanted
to interview me, meet me, or take a photo.
Great things are happening.
The love from the people out there.
Getting love
from the entire soccer community.
The Mexican University of Sport
awards an honorary doctorate.
I had promised this one to my dad.
No, come on.
Henry Kissinger who, man?
King Pelé, yeah, that's something.
I couldn't resist
asking him for an autograph.
I imagine Mr. Guillermo Cañedo
played a key role.
That's what I would think too, but…
Don't get me wrong,
but we can't live off past triumphs.
The '70 World Cup was over a decade ago.
At the end of the day,
the FEMEXFUT president
has to step in and establish his vision.
-You know? Yes.
-Yes.
You bet. That's life.
So we should forget
the triumphs of the 1960s?
I've become an icon.
Why not just say I need a diaper at night?
Much easier.
Oh, Mr. Guillermo.
You're no stranger to this.
You know the media, my friend.
And that reporter. Careful.
I didn't know her. Some Tania.
Did you go against Kissinger?
Or Steve Ross's daughter?
Why add more names to the list?
You're right. It's a shame.
I'll be more careful
so I'm not taken out of context.
It's decided.
We're hiring the Pumas' coaching staff.
América are the champions.
I know.
But we want Hugo to be happy.
So we're choosing
the coach he had in Mexico.
But that will piss off América's owner.
-Who also owns the World Cup.
-Yes, and who's also good at business.
And Hugo is profitable.
I'll talk to Mr. Emilio.
Please don't worry, Mr. Guillermo.
If I say yes, it'll be on my terms.
Sure, whatever you say.
I'll need all the players
to go to training camp.
-Well, as usual, right?
-For a year.
A whole year? No way.
What? What do you mean, a year, Bora?
Are you serious?
What should I do with the league?
Are you taking
my league's best players for a year?
Am I supposed to use
bench players, or what?
I coach the national team.
You do your job.
Okay. Come on, let's go!
Come on, guys!
It takes balls to ask Hugo Sánchez
to resign as captain, don't you think?
You know I can't tell Bora
who his captain should be.
Everyone in this country
knows who our leader is.
So why can't I have that title?
Maradona is Argentina's captain.
Platini is the captain of France.
Who should be the captain here?
Do the math, sir.
Now, if it can't be done, fine.
No rush. We just wait for Italy '90.
Listen, Hugo.
You have no idea what I'd do
to be my team's number 9 player.
To have scored your goals.
To have your awards, your money.
You're gifted.
With magic.
Share it.
Make your country happy, Hugo.
Do you really think you have a shot
with that fortune cookie speech?
I had to give it a try.
Okay…
Okay, Hugo.
What do you want?
Not much.
The usual.
I can't tie myself to the team's sponsors.
I have existing obligations.
Plus, with this demanding schedule
and all the friendly matches
they're setting up…
That's a lot of issues.
Okay, I'm gonna make you an offer.
This stays between us, okay?
You can do
all the commercials you want, Hugo.
Have as many obligations
as you like, okay?
As for the fuss about the captaincy,
we can leave that behind, can't we?
Hugo made a fortune from commercials.
He was no fool, and neither were others.
Just from the stadium renovations,
the contract allocations,
and the sponsorship deals,
FEMEXFUT was handling a fortune.
And there I was, in the middle of it all.
Azcárraga on one side, and the politician
managing the budget on the other.
El Tigre opened up his home,
and I was happy to share that with Susana.
So there I was, and in walks the sucker,
in his red suit, hammer in hand.
Really?
I wanted to kill him.
And look where he is now.
Making more money than Pimstein.
Or even Ernesto.
Emilio, let Chapulín
be the star in the commercials, right?
Yes, let the stadium
and access roads to Querétaro buzz.
Do it. Martín, hire him.
Well, we could include
his salary in the bid.
-It's a win-win.
-How's that coming along?
Good. Very good. We only need the vendor.
The folder is ready,
with the FEMEXFUT seal on it.
I told you.
I told you he's one of our own.
-Memo!
-What?
See, bastard?
You didn't make it easy for me
with this guy.
What's that, Mr. Guillermo? Come on.
No offense, man.
We've met before, right?
That's right.
Where? Remind me.
Acapulco.
At Paco Quintanilla's house.
Are you his wife?
I was.
Honey, I know who you are.
She was at the New Year's party,
the one in Los Angeles.
-Right. What a party, Paula. Yes.
-Yes!
Have you met Paco?
No…
Great guy. Where is he?
You were his queen.
Martín, her house in Acapulco…
It was gorgeous, honey. What a view.
-It was.
-Straight out of a magazine, a mansion.
She's worth big bucks, huh?
Oh, no. How so, sir? He's worth big bucks.
-Oh, really?
-Yes.
Honey, do you remember
the fab parties at that house?
-Sure.
-The last time they hired this musician…
-Barry Manilow.
-Right. Do you remember? It was wild.
Princesses never change their tastes.
Be careful, my friend.
Look at me and my Verito.
Everything on a silver platter.
No, Vero. I love silver platters.
It's the jerks I can't stand.
All right, then. Enough gossip.
I'll take the gentlemen for a chat.
Excuse us, ladies. Move.
Hey, honey, I need to know.
-Who kept the house?
-Paco. Paco kept the house.
No. I have the best lawyer, you know?
If you want…
-Hey… Sorry, babe. I couldn't hold back.
-Hey, no.
No need to apologize. That guy is a jerk.
You have no clue who Paco is.
-No. I don't want to know.
-Drive safe.
-What? Are you leaving too?
-Yes, Paula. Thank you.
-A pleasure.
-It was delicious. Superb.
-You, I need your number…
-Martín.
Despite all the hiccups, the truth is,
everything was going great…
until, just nine months
before the World Cup, this happened.
September 19, 1985.
The magnitude of the earthquake
is 8.1 on the Richter scale.
It happened at 7:19 this morning.
The epicenter is
at 16.5° north latitude
and 10.3° west longitude.
Mexico's pain is FIFA's pain, Martín.
We want you to know
we'll always stand with you.
Thank you, João.
Your words are very welcome. Thank you.
To show how much we care,
we want you to focus
on what matters most now.
We're on it, João. We are.
So we want all of your resources
and energy focused on your people.
João, you're not taking
the Cup away from us, are you?
The worst-case scenario right now
would be losing the World Cup.
Honey, everyone is terrified right now.
Let things settle down.
You'll be able to move forward
more calmly.
This country needs a reason to rise again.
And it's right here! Right here!
I need…
I need a good pitch for Emilio.
He'll see me for five minutes…
…are still trapped.
On Juárez Avenue,
there is also a lot of debris.
On Jalisco Street, a building collapsed…
I'm sorry, honey.
The hotel has broken windows…
I'm losing my mind.
…the Hotel De Carlo also collapsed…
Come.
Many people are still trapped
and have not been rescued
from the rooftops and terraces.
I repeat, this is the situation
in Mexico City.
I just need to call Mayrita
to arrange a meeting with Emilio for me.
It'll be quick, okay?
In the streets of Monterrey,
a large area is currently cordoned off.
Put Mayrita on.
Mr. De la Torre, her boss. Put her on.
What do you mean?
No, we all have emergencies.
It's an earthquake,
but you can't leave work hanging.
Okay, have someone
put me through to Mr. Azcárraga, please.
Just find him!
It's not official yet,
but they might move it to Germany.
Also, the Italians and the French
have already volunteered.
The inspections need to be rushed
to prove the stadium structures
are intact.
We'll need to keep repair costs low
to avoid drawing attention.
Shit! Seriously?
You're talking about stadiums!
While you're sipping
your nice cup of coffee,
who knows how many people
are buried under Chapultepec's rubble.
My people!
I know this is a tragedy, Mr. Emilio.
You don't have to tell me that.
And it has hit you and the company hard.
It may sound harsh, but someone
needs to think about the future.
It's important.
This damn country is in mourning.
We need something to hold on to.
I know soccer can be idiotic, okay?
Twenty-two dummies chasing a stupid ball.
But there are only a few things
that bring that kind of damn joy,
that fleeting moment of hope when,
even while losing, we think we can win.
Goddammit, Mr. Emilio! That's gold!
What am I saying?
You know this. You're the best at it.
What are you thinking?
If Guillermo
brings us his buddy Havelange,
I'll make sure we keep the World Cup.
Trust me, please.
Can we really trust you?
Well, yes. Of course you can trust me.
If FIFA comes, you can't lose focus.
Why would I lose focus?
Some matters
are better handled without women.
You do know your girlfriend's little joke
cost us with Minister Valenzuela.
Yeah, I owe you both an apology.
So damn embarrassing.
On top of it, in your house, Mr. Emilio.
No…
As we walked out,
that stupid relationship was over.
We'd had problems for a while,
but I don't know what got into me.
Actually, I do know… Those goddamn skirts.
Skirts.
But it's over. I'm focused now.
Memo, can you contact Havelange?
Sure, I'll take care of it.
Okay. Don't screw this up, Martín.
You tell the most powerful man in Mexico
what he wants to hear.
Besides, we had to focus
on Hermann Neuberger,
the FIFA official sent to assess
whether we could keep the World Cup.
Welcome to FEMEXFUT.
How was your flight?
Long.
We should get coffee, right?
Would you like some? Coffee.
This is Mexican Talavera pottery.
The FIFA committee
has reviewed this thoroughly.
We're deeply sorry about recent events,
but the World Cup
cannot take place here, gentlemen.
Two days earlier,
there had been a meeting in Switzerland.
Look at this tragedy.
And you know what?
I would have done
the same as that damn gringa.
Since you're here,
we'd like to show you around the city.
Shall we?
Right now, the whole world
is talking about
how this city has collapsed,
but there's something the newspapers
and TV news
don't want you to know, Hermann.
We want to show it to you.
Come on!
Move, Mike. Go.
It's not easy, right?
-And…
-Shift the column!
Those people are citizens, huh?
Citizens helping other citizens.
We're here so you don't hear from others
and you see it yourself.
Now we want to invite you to the stadium.
It's nearby. Twenty minutes away.
It was 20 minutes away
because we had asked the president
to block the entire freeway.
While we were at it,
we covered the potholes.
All right.
-This way.
-Let's go.
Please.
The Neza 86 Stadium,
intact and renovated
for our World Cup. Come.
Truth is, we only gave the stadium
a little touch-up.
But 20,000 food packages
and a shitload of fun
helped us stage a full crowd.
What do you think? Let me see that.
Hermann!
Thank you for being here, okay? Thank you.
Want to speak first, Hermann?
-Go ahead. Tell them.
-Please.
No, man…
Good morning.
Thank you very much for coming.
I would like to start
by saying that if I am here today,
it is because, like you, I was lucky.
Lucky in a way my neighbors were not.
And all those nights and days
that I'm sure, like you,
I spent removing debris,
searching for bodies,
I thought, "I have a responsibility."
This country deserves to believe.
The World Cup has to stay in Mexico!
So, Mr. Neuberger,
as you can see,
this stadium is in perfect condition.
But that's not what this is about.
It's about these people.
These individuals who have gathered
here today voluntarily, to remind us
that we are ready
to welcome the whole world
and celebrate on a grand scale.
Am I right?
Yes, Mr. Neuberger,
the earthquake struck us,
but it did not bring us down.
That is why this country
deserves to host and celebrate
the greatest World Cup ever held!
Welcome to Mexico, Hermann!
Goal, man. Goal!
Look, Hermann, a little something, okay?
For your decision.
Thank you.
This guy!
See, you just needed to focus, man.
Yeah, right?
Women are not the damn problem, Martín.
Take me, for example. If there's one thing
I'm crazy about, it's women.
But that doesn't mean
I'll let them walk all over me.
And it's not as hard as you think.
Look, at a certain point in life, the key
is just to get organized, you know?
That's all.
Now, if you're really lovestruck,
you know, we can help you out, okay?
I don't understand shit, Mr. Emilio. What?
Look, from now until the World Cup,
you'll be everywhere.
Lots of events, lots of cameras.
Look how excited you get, asshole.
You'll need a plus-one, okay?
Someone high-profile,
like Lucía, for instance.
You mean La Colorina?
-No, no way. No.
-Huh? No?
I'm not as badass as you.
I can't juggle two things. I'd lose focus.
Your loss.
After the opening ceremony,
I'll take you up on that.
Are you in touch with your ex?
-No, why?
-No?
No.
Paula is hung up on her house.
The one she had
with that damn Paco Quintanilla.
-Don't even tell me.
-Yep.
-I broke it off. The hell with it.
-What?
Okay. That's good.
That woman is no good for you.
Cheers, bastard.
Well done, huh?
Well done.
Babe.
Are you ready to attend
the Mexico '86 opening ceremony
in the presidential box?
You convinced him.
You should have seen him.
The sucker was ready to become Mexican.
It was insane.
And why didn't I go this time?
Just… All men, babe.
Like when the pope gets elected.
Super boring.
Okay, but I'll be there next time, right?
Or will you and I already be over by then?
What?
This morning, Paula Cussi called me to say
how sorry she was
that you and I were no longer together.
No… No way. Really?
Freaking nutcase.
You're not buying that, are you?
You were at that dinner too. She's a mess.
But it is weird, right?
What is?
I mean, Azcárraga making up
a story about us.
What's the point?
I don't know. I don't know them.
That man seems kinda dishonest, huh?
Martín.
Be honest.
I am being honest.
So, none of this happened?
I have no damn clue
what you're talking about.
-Martín.
-What?
Look…
It's not Azcárraga. It's not Paula Cussi.
You're lying to me now.
What am I supposed to say?
Damn. It pisses me off
that you don't believe me, Susana.
It hurts me.
Holy shit. Really?
What else am I supposed to do? Huh?
What else?
I have no clue what you went through
with that jerk Paco.
-But I'm not that guy, babe.
-Holy shit, Martín.
It amazes me
how you can't help but lie and lie.
Just like you judge.
So honest.
Let's talk about trust.
That's what it's about. Trust.
The wife of a criminal. A real one.
You were his wife for four years.
When was I supposed to find out?
Hmm?
Get out, Martín.
Okay.
No. Goddammit.
You bet I'm leaving! You bet!
Son of a… What an idiot. Unbelievable.
You bet I'm leaving.
So you won't feel uncomfortable,
I'll go to a ho…
Your damn keys! Here they are!
I know.
I'm an idiot.
Susana was the best thing
to happened to me,
and I took care of screwing it all up.
And that's how I stayed
until May 31, 1986.
More than 100,000 people
packed Azteca Stadium.
Who would've thought?
All those years of work, sacrifice…
The World Cup started off so well,
and I was falling apart.
And the first match,
Mexico versus Belgium.
Here comes the ball, center, and… goal!
Quirarte. Fernando Quirarte
scores the first goal…
Corner kick.
Drops it inside the box, Aguirre, goal!
Scored by Hugo Sánchez!
Fantastic goal…
Mexico's second match is against Paraguay.
Penalty for Mexico!
Hugo Sánchez stepping up,
hits the post, he missed!
Real Madrid this, Real Madrid that,
but the Azteca rules.
FALLEN IDOL
HUGOAL MISSES!
Still, we were this close
to the next round,
and everyone was happy.
Everyone but me.
-I'm here to see her.
-Go ahead.
Yes, no problem, sir.
I'll have the quote ready by five.
Sure. Thank you.
Hi.
May I? Just one minute. I'll be quick.
I have some information
that I think might be useful to you.
Mexico's quarterfinal match
will be played in Monterrey.
If we keep this up, which I think we will.
Which means that, overnight…
a shitload of people
will head to Monterrey
I mean, the flights, the travel packages…
The stadium holds 42,000 people.
A little tip.
A little friendly tip-off, huh?
Thank you.
Thank you, Martín.
Thanks for the information.
Okay…
All right… Sorry, I have to…
Susana…
Susana, I had to see you.
I miss you so much.
What we had was so beautiful.
And I blew it. I know I blew it.
I couldn't handle it.
And I let my pride get the best of me.
Forgive me, Susana.
Please forgive me.
Thank you.
Thank you for apologizing.
I know that isn't easy for you, is it?
It isn't easy.
But you know why I'm doing it?
Because I love you.
That's why.
Thank you.
Thank you
for seeing me, for giving me a chance.
Thank you.
Who says I'm giving you a chance?
No, I mean…
What?
Martín, you're a liar.
Let's be real.
You were lying to your wife when we met.
And I get it.
I'm not a saint,
and I'm not asking you to be one.
We all have our flaws.
But relationships have rules
that you still have to learn.
I applaud you.
Showing up here today was a big step.
But you still have a long way to go.
And thanks for the heads-up
about Monterrey.
Yeah.
Yeah, that'll be very useful.
Nice to see you.
You too.
Hey, thanks for making time for me.
I'm heading out. Excuse me.
-Thank you.
-Have a good day.
-Bye.
Are you asking me
to have Mexico lose to Iraq?
I'm not asking you.
Mexico will lose to Iraq
and finish second in the group.
I think it's a damn huge mistake.
Let's see. If Mexico leads the group,
they'd play in Monterrey.
The Azteca belongs to Emilio Azcárraga.
The Mexican squad
only plays in his stadium.
What part of that isn't clear?
They want the team
to play only at the Azteca.
What do you want, Martín?
I want you to score five goals.
Our team is not losing this World Cup.
Good.
I respect you, Martín.
-I respect you a lot too, Bora.
-What?
They offered you a house.
A house?
Bro…
No, that's not true.
No way, man.
They didn't offer you shit.
Dude, if you win the World Cup,
I'll marry you, man.
I'll get you a house, a minivan…
Okay, we didn't score five,
but we did score one.
And that got us
to the top of the group undefeated.
After beating Iraq,
Mexico is playing
its fourth match against Bulgaria.
We're past the 35-minute mark
and Rafael Amador's touch
aims it to Negrete,
who kicks it to Aguirre.
A wonderful volley by El Vasco.
Back to Negrete.
Negrete nails the scissor kick
and it's a goal for Negrete! Goal!
No way.
-Goal! Goal for Mexico!
-No way, Manuel!
Goal!
Goal, sucker! Goal! Holy shit!
…the best goal.
Mexico is celebrating.
For the first time, the Mexican squad
gets to a fifth game.
Quarterfinals.
El Tri faces Germany in Monterrey
in what is set to be
the most important match
in the history of Mexican soccer.
Let's go!
The referee starts the quarterfinal match
between Mexico and Germany.
Mexico has proven itself
in a fantastic match
against runner-up Germany.
Let's go, Mexico!
Cruz lands into Germany's box…
And it's a goal for Mexico!
Wait a second.
Shit. He ruled it out.
The referee calls a prior foul,
and Mexico comes up empty.
This is getting tough.
Flaco, come on!
The Mexican players
stand their ground and keep attacking.
The 90 minutes of regulation time are up,
scoreless.
The referee blows the final whistle.
Next up, penalty kicks!
Bora has two reliable takers:
Negrete and Sánchez.
But wait, Pichichi hasn't recovered.
He's been cramping up for a while.
We'll see if he kicks.
-He's not moving.
-He won't get up.
He's not moving. That asshole.
Hugo won't get up. He won't get up.
Come on, Hugo!
-He has to kick.
-He's not standing up.
No, he's getting up. Of course he is.
Wait up. I'll be right back.
Come on. Go on, man.
-Take off your jacket.
-Me?
Take off your jacket!
Good!
What a damn good job, Hugo!
Hell of a game, man! We almost got them!
The time is now, okay? Now.
Have you picked your turn?
-I wish I could, but…
-But?
I can't.
-Why?
-It's what's best for the team.
I'm cramping too badly to take one.
Best for what damn team?
You don't get cramps with Real Madrid.
-What?
-Don't back down, Hugo.
I'm not backing down, asshole.
Are you going to teach me?
It's your first time
on a damn soccer field!
What do you know about soccer?
"Back down."
Asshole.
-Bora!
-What are you doing here, dude?
So Hugo doesn't want to?
Nobody wants to kick.
I don't have Tomás, Javier, and now Hugo.
-They're terrified.
-It's their job, Bora!
Pick your best guys and make them do it.
Listen. I'm not making them.
If I do that, they'll miss.
They have to want it.
And get out of here.
Raúl, you're not kicking?
The coach decides.
People will remember you if you decide.
Who scored the best goal
of the Cup, Manolo? Who?
Who's been the best player
on this damn team, Fernando?
They're here to see you.
Are you a leader or not?
Penalty shooters are remembered.
Don't blow it! Raise your hand!
Freaking Raúl raised his hand.
You're gonna look bad.
Coach!
I'll take the first one.
-I'm going in, sir.
-Thank you.
Coach! I'll go.
-Good, Raúl, let's go.
-Good.
So there it was. We had the takers.
Now, we only needed Bora to work his magic
so we could beat Germany.
Listen to me.
I'm not like you, okay?
I wasn't born in Mexico.
But this is the country I chose.
And do you know why?
Because anything is possible here.
It's possible to beat Germany,
and anyone else, damn it!
Hell yeah!
So take the shot with guts. With heart!
We are Mexico.
And nothing is impossible here.
We can do it! Yes, we can!
Yes, we can!
GERMANY'S FAVOR
The Germans…
they always nail it.
Even though we lost,
seeing your team play like that
against one of the world's best teams
is something to be damn proud of.
That stadium turned into a party.
That World Cup was fantastic.
Although 1986 wasn't over yet,
El Tigre was mapping out the next move.
You're making history, man.
We are, Mr. Emilio. We are making history.
Hey, if our team keeps this up,
who knows, maybe we can bring
the damn Cup home from Italy, right?
But not even playing
eleven versus three, right?
Keep it up, man. Look.
-Do you like this house?
-Beautiful.
Well, it's yours, man.
That's what I do.
I know how to reward my people.
You're off to a very good start.
I'm renewing your contract with FEMEXFUT.
If you get bored,
you can join me at the company.
How about a VP position?
What an honor, Mr. Emilio.
I'd love to be by your side, but…
What?
You know I've got my sights
set on Switzerland.
No kidding.
-How will you do it? What's your plan?
-The Olympic Games are coming up.
Korea, okay? We're going for the gold.
We have a great team. The U-20 squad.
That'll be the foundation
to build a solid team for Hugo Sánchez.
Who will stop us in Italy?
Sounds good.
Look, if you pull it off,
I'll back you
so you can take João's chair.
The sucker will have to retire
at some point.
Just don't screw it up, okay?
Cardozo, we're going
to give the U-20s a hand.
Wherever Mexico shows up,
it has to kick ass.
Let's give the U-20s a hand,
and, if necessary,
the U-19s, U-17s, U-23s…
We'll include
two or three more seasoned players.
That'll do. You'll see.
Tell him that age doesn't matter now.
We'll take care of that.
Have them shave. Ask Chabelo for advice.
We got birth certificates
for quite a few veterans.
We put together a powerhouse team.
It wasn't my decision alone,
but I signed it.
By 1988, Mexico was ready
to join the First World.
And the U-20s too.
We were kicking ass.
The plan was working.
UNSTOPPABLE U-20!
But not everyone agreed.
MEXICO IS NOW A POWERHOUSE
Five, four, three, two…
Special report.
This morning, Guatemala filed a protest
against overage players in the U-20.
GUATEMALA PRESSURES CONCACAF
CONCACAF will review the case
and determine the consequences
of this shameful fraud.
…this bastard.
The U-20 has overage players.
How can you appeal?
That's slander.
Groundless claims
are a betrayal of the country.
-You have proof, show it.
-Your signature.
You're here to mess with me, right?
That's why you're here. We're done.
Get out. Cardozo, see him out.
Damn little prick.
You came to ruin this, asshole.
-Out.
-Don't touch me.
Nobody's pushing you, man. Okay? Get out.
So please tell me the truth
about the birth certificates.
Were they forged or not?
We…
did not forge any certificates.
This sanction against Mexico
is the harshest
ever imposed in FIFA's history.
I'm only going to say one thing.
Moral decline and corruption
in Mexican soccer
come down to one person,
Martín de la Torre.
That's all. Anything else?
Do you know how much money I'm losing
by missing Italy 90?
Any idea what missing a World Cup
does to a nation's morale?
Especially with the team
being at its peak.
Hugo has the Golden Boot, damn it!
If you cared, why didn't you defend me?
We'd still be going to Italy 90!
Who the hell
do you think you are, asshole?
Do I owe you or what?
I delivered
the most epic World Cup in history.
That's all.
And there's loyalty.
I mean, that's no small thing,
Mr. Emilio. Right?
Did I ever say anything
about any of your scams?
I didn't, did I?
I kept quiet. I could've talked.
I still can.
Now you're threatening me.
Bastard. I made you.
You're nothing in soccer without me.
You don't know a thing about soccer!
You don't see it.
We're done here.
If you don't appreciate me,
you can go fuck yourself.
You are ballsy, you bastard.
But now every door is going
to close on you.
You're taking the fall for this alone.
I'll make the whole country
spit in your face. Do you understand?
Do you think I'm afraid of you, Emilio?
With your stupid little power,
your stupid little company.
Soccer is for men, damn it!
Let's fucking go, huh?
You and me. Right now! Get up!
Come on! Now that you're alone!
Get up, damn it! Get up!
So is that all you've got?
I'm not one of your stupid showgirls.
Don't get it twisted.
You can keep soccer.
We'll see how fast you blow it.
Like everything else. Coward.
Hey, are you Martín de la Torre?
Then go fuck yourself!
MEXICO CITY, 1994
-What's up, buddy?
-What's up, sir?
Pour me a double. I'm leaving soon.
Not watching it today?
-You know the drill.
-Okay, so no.
I don't enjoy watching the team anymore.
-Here you go, sir.
-Thank you.
It hurts me.
But since '86,
the team hasn't been the same.
The fans have been there
through thick and thin.
The World Cup was a huge success.
Televisa made big money.
The whole nation was proud.
There's been nothing like it since.
But the system is brutal.
I was banned from soccer for life.
And the country bought the story
that we missed Italy 90 because of me.
But life hasn't been
so bad for me. It hasn't.
FEMEXFUT was riddled
with internal politics,
and soccer was draining.
Nevertheless, I…
I don't regret a thing.
Many would've loved
to mastermind the World Cup that changed
the history of the World Cup.
They can't fool me. I was there.
Excuse me, are you Martín de la Torre?
Then why don't you go fuck yourself?
Okay…
Buddy, let me pay.
No, end of the month works better.
I have to go. I have a match.
Luckily, some games
won't let you go that easily.
You just need to know the rules.
-Hello, ma'am.
-Hi.
Is your husband home?
No.
Who are you anyway?
Hugo Sánchez.
Hugo?
Why? Aren't you supposed
to be playing against Bulgaria?
No.
It's halftime. I snuck out.
I'm here to score a little goal.
Just one?
MARTÍN DE LA TORRE
SPENT THE REST OF HIS LIFE
TEACHING ACCOUNTING
AFTER HIS TIME AT FEMEXFUT,
MEXICAN SOCCER WAS UPGRADED
TO A PROFESSIONAL LEVEL
SINCE THEN, THE MEXICAN NATIONAL TEAM
HAS QUALIFIED FOR EVERY WORLD CUP
AND IT HAS NEVER COME
SO CLOSE TO WINNING IT
AS IT DID WITH MARTÍN DE LA TORRE.
INSPIRED BY EL 86: EL AÑO
EN QUE MÉXICO CAMBIÓ AL MUNDO